# **RORY GALPIN**

Security Engineer, Google

+353833294751 • +447532180299 rorymgalpin@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/rorygalpin

### **EXPERIENCE**

## Security Engineer, Google

September 2020 - PRESENT

- Keeping Alphabet secure by discovering all vulnerabilities and enabling asset owners to fix them in a timely manner
- Analysing and triaging new incidents, determining threat level and priority, providing owners with clear redemption steps and support to resolve the issue
- Automating team operations, allowing focus on critical issues

# Corporate Engineering (IT Resident), Google

July 2019 - PRESENT

- Supporting Google's global infrastructure and employees
- Pursuing a focussed pathway in Security Engineering and Analysis
- Analysing and visualising new patterns of the distribution of malware with Google's Trust and Safety Team
- Analysing data in aim to utilise an existing forum as a new Support Channel, optimising Engineer's coverage and effort
- Maintaining and analysing internal services in aim to improve and or automate current systems and workflows
- Organising and leading site wide quality assurance sessions to keep standards consistently high. Developed training - adopted globally
- Automated "health" checks on Corporate machines, alerting Technical Support with the issue and resolution steps
- Mentor and trainer for new-starters

# Technical Specialist (Genius Bar), Apple

July 2018 - July 2019

- Identifying and solving complex iOS, MacOS and hardware issues
- Consistently high customer satisfaction reviews
- Delivered on the job training for new-starters

### **EDUCATION**

# Computer Security and Forensics, BSc (Hons), University of Greenwich September 2016 - June 2019

- Graduated with First Class Honours
- Selected to present Dissertation and Project at London's CRESTCon
- Liaised with the British Computing Society (BCS) to ensure the course upholds the BCS Accreditation
- Program and Event Manager Computing Society

### **SUMMARY**

Security Engineer at Google's EU HQ. 1st Class Computer Security and Forensics graduate. Experienced in security vulnerability management, engineering and project management. Highly experienced with Linux and MacOS. Passionate about making teams more efficient by analysing and exploring data, and improving and automating internal processes.

### **SKILLS**

- Project Management
- Customer Service
- Root Cause Analysis
- · Security Analysis
- Penetration Testing
- Data Analytics
- MacOS, Linux & Windows
- iWork, GSuite & Office365
- Qualys Scanners
- Nessus Vulnerability Assessment
- OSINT
- Automation

#### **PROGRAMMING**

- Python
- Embedded C / C
- SQI
- HTML / CSS / JS
- PowerShell / Bash Scripting

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

- CompTIA Security+ CompTIA, August 2020
- SIEM Tools
  Cybrary, August 2020
- SOC Analyst Level 2 Cybrary, July 2020
- Offensive Penetration Testing Cybrary, July 2020
- Autopsy Digital Forensics
  Basis Tech, May 2020
- Robotics (Embedded C)
  UoG, June 2016

### **REFERENCES**

Available on request